

Chesnokov Andrii

QA Engineer

Location: Kiev, Ukraine

Phone (Telegram, WhatsApp): +38 (050) 460-60-65

E-mail: chesnokov.andrewqa@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Andrew Chesnokov

Skype: live:.cid.3a362ca5c7f6e16e

Git: Andrew Chesnokov

Goal: Position of Junior QA Engineer, with the possibility of professional

growth

Summary:

Quality Assurance Engineer with practical experience in testing WEB applications, auto-tests creation using Java, API testing using RESTer and Postman. Owing to my previous experience at managerial position, I can set priorities in the work process. I have the ability to establish effective relationships with colleagues and clients. I have initiative, perseverance, and energy in achieving goals. I approach with responsibility in the implementation of professional solutions. I have the ability to learn and work hard.

Skills:

- Experience in creation of QA documentation: Test Plans, Test Cases and Bug Reports
- Understanding of software development lifecycle, QA process
- Understanding of Agile (Scrum) methodologies
- Experience with Bug Tracking Systems :Mantis, JIRA
- Experience with Test Management Systems: TestLink, TestRail
- Experience with Selenium WebDriver, TestNG
- Understanding of web structure(HTML,CSS), Chrome devTools
- Understanding of Postman(GET,POST,PUT,DELETE)
- Experience with version control system : GitHub (basic commands)
- Basic knowledge of Java SE, OOP principles.
- Experience with OS: Windows, Linux(Ubuntu)
- Experience with Oracle VM VirtualBox

Experience:

Software Tester, PetStore "BestFriends", January 2023 - February 2023

- Developing and executing test cases in TestRail, checklists, test plan
- Web testing
- Reporting bugs(Jira, Mantis)

Software Tester, Swag Labs, December 2022 - February 2023

- Creation and execution of auto-tests using JavaSE(Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Maven)
- Functional testing

Software Tester, ListBoxer, May 2022 – June 2022

- Requirements analysis
- Test case development and execution
- Functional testing, usability testing

• Bug reporting(Jira)

Sales and Customer Experience Manager, "Vodafone Retail" LLC, May 2018 – October 2020

- Servicing B2B and B2C subscribers of the "VF Ukraine" company, holding negotiations, conclusion of agreements in the interests of the company
- Training new employees
- Participating in a website content creation(Magento)
- Working with FORIS, SIEBEL, JRM, Microsoft Dynamics Nav, PowerBI,1C:ERP
- Representative of "VF Ukraine" company at WeGame expo (2019) Sales Manager, "DNIPRO-M", October 2021- March 2022

Additional education:

2022-2023 GeeksForLess Inc., IT outsource company (with certificate)

Automation QA course

2023 QATestLab, IT outsource company. (with certificate)

Fundamentals of Software Testing

2022 Prog.Academy educational center of IT specialists (with certificates)

QA Courses: 1) QA Start(Manual QA)

2) Java Start + QA Automation

2015 Certified English Courses: Pearson test of English general Edexcel Level I Certificate in ESOL

International (CEF B2) (with certificate)

Education:

2014-2021 Name of the Education Establishment: State University of Telecommunications

Program Subject Area: Telecommunications and Radio Engineering

Degree (diploma): Master

Professional Qualification: Telecommunications Engineer

Languages:

English – Upper-Intermediate (B2)

Ukrainian – native speaker

Russian – native speaker